<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>In the news on #Imbizo - Simons Computational Neuroscience Imbizo</title><link>/news/</link><description>Recent content in In the news on #Imbizo - Simons Computational Neuroscience Imbizo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:44:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Neuroscience Network Across Continents</title><link>/news/a-neuroscience-network-across-continents/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:44:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>/news/a-neuroscience-network-across-continents/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A gathering to share knowledge”: Imbizo’s founders chose this Xhosa word to name their computational neuroscience summer school in South Africa and the African continent. Since co-founding Imbizo in 2016, Institute of Science and Technology Austria (ISTA) Professor Tim Vogels has attracted bright minds to both Imbizo and ISTA. Four Imbizo alumni with ties to ISTA tell how their unique experience led them to be at the core of an intercontinental neuroscience network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The 2020 BiasWatchNeuro Award for Equity and Inclusivity</title><link>/news/biaswatchneuro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 20:15:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/biaswatchneuro/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This year, we announced a new annual recognition for neuroscience or neuroscience-related departments, institutes and programs that demonstrate the exceptional creation of a culture where individuals underrepresented and/or marginalized in STEM feel integral to the community and thrive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Summer School in Africa Breaks Barriers in Neuroscience</title><link>/news/simons-summer-school/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 12:14:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/news/simons-summer-school/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How we facilitate the formation of a cohesive community that transcends race, gender and geographic boundaries in just three weeks&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brains by the sea: Computational neuroscience gains a foothold in Africa</title><link>/news/brains-by-the-sea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 12:14:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/news/brains-by-the-sea/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/images/news/scimag-logo.png" width="200px"/>

&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The rich waters of False Bay, near Cape Town in South Africa, have sustained nomadic human tribes for tens of thousands of years. But over the last three years it has also become the starting point of an African journey to answer one of humanity’s great unsolved questions: how does the brain work?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Think: Theory for Africa</title><link>/news/think-theory-for-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 12:14:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/news/think-theory-for-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/images/news/thinktheoryinafrica.png" alt="computational neuroscience by country">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the century of the brain, African scientists and educators are poised to make important contributions to global neuroscience research. We believe that theoretical sciences, and specifically computational and theoretical neuroscience are the ideal discipline for the African continent&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>